

- +420777873412
- olyaarsenych@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/olha-arsenych-6b9576157/

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Applied Mathematics**

National Technical University of Ukraine "Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

2013 - 2017

Master of Applied Informatics Prague University of Economics and Business

2018 - 2020

## **EXPERTISE**

Software

Development

Test

**Automation** 

APIs

Database administration

# USED TECHNOLOGIES

Git, Docker, Jenkins, ReadyApi, Postman, Elasticsearch, AWS, Azure

Gradle, Spring, TestNG, Rest Assured, Hibernate

#### LANGUAGE

English Czech Ukrainian

# **ARSENYCH OLHA**

Software Engineer

### **ABOUT ME**

I work as a Software Backend Engineer on the Fortify SSC. I'm responsible for adding features, fixing bugs, and optimizing database performance using Java, Gradle, Spring, Hibernate, and other tools. Additionally, I have four years of experience as a Test Automation Engineer, mainly programming on Java using Rest Assured and TestNG as my primary tools.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Jun 2022- Present

OpenText/Micro Focus | Prague

#### Software Engineer

Writing server-side code in Java to handle business logic, data processing, and database(SQL) interactions. Designing, implementing, and maintaining RESTful API. Creating and optimizing database schemas, writing SQL queries, and using Hibernate to interact with databases. Identifying and resolving performance bottlenecks in the backend code, such as optimizing database queries and improving response times.

2019 - Jun 2022

Micro Focus | Prague

# Test Automation Engineer

Designing and implementing test automation frameworks from scratch in Java. Creating and configuring test environments. Managing test data and databases for comprehensive test coverage, generating and manipulating test data to simulate various scenarios. Creating and maintaining test plans, test cases, and test scripts documentation.

Creating and maintaining automated test scripts for functional, regression, and performance testing.

Integrating automated tests into CI/CD pipelines using tool like Jenkins.

2018 - 2019

NVision | Prague

#### Test Engineer

Integration, functional and stress testing of new features for SCP (Service Control Point) in telecommunication. Implementation of automated and units tests in C# on development stand, using host framework for testing – Husky tests. SCP components integration and modules configuration. Customer interactions via features presentations and other product related queries.

2017

Intellectual Communications, Giraffe | Kyiv Junior IT specialist

Database administrative activities around PL/SQL – Oracle. Fully manage department documentation.